okay um lead code practice time
so still two things
so the first one is to find the approach
for this problem
and the other thing is to see how to
solve this problem
in a proper way in the code interview
in interview
so let's take a look at the question two
sum so give an array of the integers
nums and the integer target return the
indices of
two numbers such that they add up to
target and you may assume that each
input
would have exactly one solution and you
may not use the same element twice
and you can return the answer in any
other
so first thing first is to clarify the
ambiguities
and think about the ash cases so the
first one
is i always say always to ask
questions to clarify
and think about the ash cases
so for this one uh it is well it is very
well defined
but if the conditions
highlighted here is not given um
please ask questions um because they're
very good questions
to discuss with the interviewer so like
what what if there is more than one
solution or
no solution at all for a given input uh
is it okay to use the same element twice
and how to return the return value
is there any other we need to follow
so those are very good questions so
after we clarify the ambiguities
and we have finished
thinking about the edge cases that can
potentially happen
um it is a time for us to think about
the solution
so the second one is to
think about solution
so during this time it is always
recommended to think aloud
but if you prefer to think silently
please indicate with your interviewer
like please give me seven minutes to
think
um so that's that's also fine so there's
no
um hard regulation uh how you think
but uh i would recommend you to think
about even if it is not
perfect at this moment even if it is
just a brutal solution
so feel free to talk a lot because at
least you will have a workable approach
at that time and also during the time
you talk with your interior if it is too
hard
to explain the approach in english you
can feel free to use
uh uh some other ways so for example
you can go through an example to explain
how your approach is going to work on it
or you can draw some graph if it's easy
for you to draw something there
so how to solve this problem um
so the profile solution we can see is we
can do
a for loop within another for loop to
traverse the
input array then it is going to have
uh n square as the time complexity and
the
constant as the space complexity
it's not good because runtime is too
long
so think about how to optimize it so we
can use a hashmap
so we can keep record of the numbers
we iterate uh from the input array
in the hashmap uh and then we look at
the number
uh we are iterating in the input array
we see whether there is a number
within the hashmap that has a value as
target
minus the number from the interior
you're currently looking at if yes
that's pretty much the solution you're
looking at
otherwise you just keep going through
the
input array until you find the final
solution
so um now we have
the solution ready here and it's time
for us to do some coding so for coding
so for coding parts we need to care
about
our code correctness
and your code readability
so is so so
both are very important during recording
interview
because if you don't have the correct
code then um
like you don't think about some ash
cases and then
um it would be a red flag during the
interview if your code
uh doesn't look very good so for example
the naming convention is not
very good uh or like the formatting is
not very good
then it may also hurt um
so let's uh write some code for this
question so first of all
um we need to have a hash map
let's call it value index map
now we need to go through the input
array
because we need to use index so we will
use the index based traversing so i is
equal to zero
is smaller than i minus
is smaller than non dot lens plus plus i
so um so first is to check whether there
is a value
in the hashmap which is target minus
nums i so we can say
we had defined a remain value as local
variable
as target minus nums i
and if we already have it
in the valley index map
then that's the solution we are going to
return so
now we are going to return the
the solution which is first element
is i and the second one is value index
map
dot get
otherwise uh we are we are going to put
the current element into the
value next map
and then continue to put
nums i as key and i as value
so now it's pretty much
finished but since java is going to
give us some compile arrow if we don't
return
something here
so we are going to return something here
so let's say we return a minus one minus
one
at the end so that's pretty much it for
this code
um after your code complete and you're
pretty confident
please talk with your interviewer
because the next part
is about testing
so how to test this usually you choose a
simple
input example go through it and explain
how it works
on this piece of code so let's say we
use 2 7
11 15 which is the first example given
by this website target as nine
so let's say first of all we initialize
a uh empty hash map when i
is equal to zero then target
minus nums i is nine minus two which is
seven
and since the uh the map
is empty at this moment uh we are not
going to touch
this f branch we are going to put
2 as a key and 0 as a value into this
hash map and when i is equal to 1
then target minus numps i
is 9 minus 7 which is 2 so 2
already exists in the value index map so
we are going to return one and zero as a
final solution
so it works for this given input
um so then so after doing some sanity
track by going through this manually uh
we need to think about some other test
cases to increase the task coverage
so like this one we can say
example 3 is a pretty good good
input case because it has two numbers
and
they are exactly the same um
otherwise i cannot think of some other
fancy task cases out of the top of my
head that is helpful for the test
coverage
so let's give it a shot by running this
code
okay so that's it for this coding
question
i hope you enjoy this video and find it
a little bit helpful so if you like it
please like and share with other people
and also give me a thumb up and i'll see
you
in the next video